

My Contact

 \bowtie

alfreolico.brambila@gmail.com

+52-938-1448996



Priv. 53 A #7 Col. Electricistas



https://www.linkedin.com/in/alfredobrambila-arias/

Hard Skill

- Work in 3D design (computer-aided design, or "CAD")
- Sound knowledge of engineering fundamentals
- Work to improve and maintain existing products
- Proactive and willing to take on new challenges

Soft Skill

- Observation
- Decision making
- Communication
- Active listening skills
- Writing skills
- Patience

Education Background

 Universidad Tecnológica de Campeche
Certified SOLIDWORKS Associate in Mechanical Design

Completed in 2022

Danfoss

Técnico Certificado Danfoss Completed in 2022

Niagara College Canada
Teaching English as a Foreign Language
Completed in 2020

Universidad Tecnológica de Campeche
Certified SOLIDWORKS Associate in Mechanical
Design

Completed in 2022

Languages

English

Alfredo Brambila Arias

Mechanical Engineer

About Me

Dedicated mechanical engineer with knowledge of technologies and tools in mechanical design using SolidWorks and engineering. 9 years of experience in education. Problem-solving and analytical skills and ability to identify the root cause of issues and implement creative, targeted solutions. Seekeing to leverage my expertise to join to the Company

Professional Experience

COSL MEXICO | PURCHASER 2023 - Present

Key responsibilities:

- Sourcing suppliers based on price, availability, necessity, quality and logistical expenses
- Assessing vendors and their offerings with in-person visits, interviews and analysis to assess their quality
- Collaborating with various internal departments to ensure that they fulfill all customer requests
- Negotiating sale agreements and supply contracts in ways that benefit their company
- Coordinating with shipping agencies and sellers to ensure timely deliveries and oversee the integrity and quality of delivered goods and services

UTCAM | Teacher 2014 - 2023

Key responsibilities:

- Teaching technical subjects of in BIS model.
- · Planning and preparing lessons.
- Create and distribute educational content (notes, summaries, assignments etc.).
- Plan and execute educational in-class and outdoor activities and events
- Tutoring and counseling activities for the groups.
- Academic advisor for students' internship activities.
- Supervisor of internship reports.

Integral Solutions Services | Field Engineer 2012 – 2014

Key responsibilities:

- Creation of blueprints using CAD (computer-aided design).
- Convert basic design information and requirements into working drawings.
- Writing reports and documentation.

Vallen | H2S Specialist Technician 2011 – 2012

Key responsibilities:

- Safety talks to offshore facility personnel.
- Teach the procedure for the correct use of SCBA's.
- Monitoring of the presence of toxic or combustible gas in offshore facilities.
- Minor maintenance of electric and diesel compressors.

Achievements

2017 – 2022 Planning and organization of the CICAUTCAM International Congresses.